<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PureBeauty</title>
    <description>minimalistic, sexy, beautiful (jekyll) theme.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 17:25:57 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 17:25:57 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Drive for backup small databases</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;this-tutorial-is-for-unix-distros-but-you-can-adapt-to-your-needs&quot;&gt;This tutorial is for unix distros, but you can adapt to your needs.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I need to backup a small client database and needed to do it fast and easy. So I think on the first thing that help me when I think on backup or send a file: Google Drive. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Client OS is Debian 8.3 (jessie) and I have installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prasmussen/gdrive&quot;&gt;gdrive project&lt;/a&gt; to manage upload. All you need to do is download a binary and install on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuring-gdrive&quot;&gt;Configuring gdrive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After install/copy binary, only thing left to do is run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gdrive about&lt;/code&gt; and follow program instruction to generate token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-target-folder&quot;&gt;Create target folder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we need to create a folder to upload our files to google drive, do it using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gdrive&lt;/code&gt; by command:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gdrive mkdir &amp;lt;folder&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; this way you will receive an output like this &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Directory 0BwFhcg1_acLiemZENlQ5Z2Vpd2c created&lt;/code&gt;. Save that hash and go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pg_dump-command&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2893954/how-to-pass-in-password-to-pg-dump&quot;&gt;pg_dump command&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that you know how to export a dump from your database and pg_dump is how I export from postgres. So let’s talk about it. For avoid pg_dump to ask password every time you’ll need to create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.pgpass&lt;/code&gt; file on home folder of the user that will execute your command, if you’ll put it in a cronjob, you can export a environment variable and export using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--dbname&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;using .pgpass:
create &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.pgpass&lt;/code&gt; file, write &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;localhost:5432:mydbname:postgres:mypass&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chmod 600 .pgpass&lt;/code&gt;
then
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_dump &amp;gt; last_backup.sql&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;using environment variable:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;export MYDB=postgresql://username:password@127.0.0.1:5432/mydatabase&lt;/code&gt;
then
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_dump --dbname=$MYDB &amp;gt; last_backup.sql&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concat-all-the-things&quot;&gt;concat all the things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_dump --dbname=$MYDB &amp;gt; /root/last_backup.sql &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ts=$(eval date +&quot;%x_%T&quot;); gdrive upload -p 0BwFhcg1_acLiemZENlQ5Z2Vpd2c --name &quot;last_backup_${ts}&quot; /root/last_backup.sql&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-explain-the-command&quot;&gt;let’s explain the command:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pg_dump for export database to file &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/root/last_backup.sql&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ts variable with current date assigned;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now on gdrive upload you’ll use that hash copied from gdrive mkdir command, –name argument is for name on google drive after upload, here we use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ts&lt;/code&gt; variable to diff backup names, otherwise we’ll see only a lot of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;last_backup&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create a script put this code and check integrity comparing previous dump size or something fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all folks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/gdrive-backup-small-databases/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/gdrive-backup-small-databases/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PSVita buttons isn't working on applications</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-think-about-what-youre-doing-do-it-calm-and-focused-if-youve-warranty-just-send-it&quot;&gt;First, think about what you’re doing, do it calm and focused. If you’ve warranty just send it.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, My Playstation Vita stop working as expected. I was searching all the internet for any way to fix what looks like a software (firmware) problem. Basically, square, circle, left buttons won’t work for any reason, BUT only in applications, if I hold ps button to open enable/disable wifi page everything works fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I found this on EU PSN community:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://community.eu.playstation.com/t5/PS-Vita-Support/ps-vita-buttons-not-working/m-p/17605424&quot;&gt;PS Vita buttons not working (EU PSN Community)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It leads me to the first thing to do: go to safe mode and try every option there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;turn off the psvita, so press power while holding the PS Button and the right shoulder button (Safe mode)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can’t help me in any way and now I was thinking in throw psv away when I found &lt;strong&gt;@mikmoe&lt;/strong&gt; first comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey guys I also came across this error with my vita buttons only working on the menu and not an actual game. Unlike most I refuse to pay 150$ to send it in and then wait a month to get a new one. So i took it apart and found the problem and its a easy and cheap fix. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read entire comment if you want to understand what he’s explaining.
This comment made me doubt my firmware tesis and I was thinking about something on hardware (it’s really odd, because the buttons is working outside apps.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In minutes I was watching this video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWpeZVH1DXw&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;Sony Playstation Vita Self Repair Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a how to take apart your playstation vita. Now I can f*ck up my psvita myself. I bought a precision screwdriver and start disassembly it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this now and thinking: “ow, f*ck… I can’t do this.” there’s something you need to know: it’s REALLY easy. (remember, do it calm and focused, if you prefer write where every screw goes or take a photo of every step)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is follow the video until when he remove the left and right boards, there’s our problem (or should be), you don’t need to open entire thing. I just remove the left and right boards (after remove all the screws and flat cables) and clean up both connections using alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can mount it, go to safe mode, recreate database, wait a little, pray a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My PS Vita come back to work flawlessly after that, I hope you can ressurect yours too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to ps player @mikmoe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/20/psvita-buttons-isnt-working-on-applications/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/02/20/psvita-buttons-isnt-working-on-applications/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ProjectSH for lazy people</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;deprecated-im-using-z-project-instead-thanks-to-stavros&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Deprecated] I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rupa/z/&quot;&gt;z&lt;/a&gt; project instead. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://stavros.io/&quot;&gt;@stavros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever need to change from one project to another? If you get yourself writing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd ../../ [...]&lt;/code&gt; just to go somewhere else to execute one command or cat a file or something else, I know your pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, a friend point me to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;direnv&lt;/code&gt; project, an environment switcher for the shell, and things start make sense for me. When I go to a folder, direnv automagically execute a script to configure/initialize things, so I just need to start coding. Everything was beautiful until I start programming in projects using API + front-end as separated projects, now things start being annoying again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;normal people: open one terminal, open two tabs, on first tab open things from project 1, maybe tiled on tmux maybe not, on second tab open things from project 2. Hard lift is just switch between tabs.
Think this way, you are on tab 1, writing things to your front-end project using vim, so you realize that a migration is missing on your API and need to go to another project. It will be nice if we have something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ goto project2

/* edit some things */
/* execute commands */

$ goto project1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or if you are lazy like me: Imagine that you just woke up and will start programming, when you open the terminal, need to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; to your project folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I write a solution for me (maybe only my problem). I just called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/StefanYohansson/projectsh&quot;&gt;projectsh&lt;/a&gt;, it’s an easy jump between projects and it’s easy to use (at least for me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just need to go into your project 1 folder and type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd /where/is/project1
$ projectsh --add project1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;same for project2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd /where/is/project2
$ projectsh --add project2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now if you are on project1 or anywhere, you just need to run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ projectsh project2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and magically it will &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into project2 folder.
If you want to remove a project index, run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ projectsh --remove project1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using direnv, it will be awesome, you will run projectsh to go into a folder and direnv auto load the environment (from .direnv file) for you. Now, it’s time to work without run thousands of commands everytime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/23/projectsh-for-lazy-people/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/23/projectsh-for-lazy-people/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
